{
  "heading": "Questions and Answers",
  "topics": [
    {
      "heading": "Letter consonants and Consonant blends",
      "questions": [
        {
          "questionNo": 1,
          "question": "Which of the following words contains a three-letter consonant blend?",
          "options": [
            "brick",
            "strong",
            "plant",
            "frog"
          ],
          "answer": 1,
          "explanation": "The word \"strong\" contains the three-letter consonant blend \"str.\""
        },
        {
          "questionNo": 2,
          "question": "Identify the consonant blend in the word \"flight\":",
          "options": [
            "fl",
            "li",
            "ig",
            "All of the above"
          ],
          "answer": 0,
          "explanation": "This is because \"fl\" at the beginning of the word consists of two consonants pronounced together, retaining their sounds."
        },
        {
          "questionNo": 3,
          "question": "Which word has a three-letter consonant blend?",
          "options": [
            "score",
            "scare",
            "scratch",
            "scarf"
          ],
          "answer": 2,
          "explanation": "The word \"scratch\" contains the consonant blend \"scr.\""
        },
        {
          "questionNo": 4,
          "question": "The word \"bribe\" contains a three-letter consonant blend.",
          "options": [
            "True",
            "False"
          ],
          "answer": 1,
          "explanation": "The word \"bribe\" contains a two-letter consonant blend \"br.\""
        },
        {
          "questionNo": 5,
          "question": "Which of the following words does not contain a consonant blend?",
          "options": [
            "trap",
            "clip",
            "bat",
            "drink"
          ],
          "answer": 2,
          "explanation": "The word \"bat\" does not contain a consonant blend."
        },
        {
          "questionNo": 6,
          "question": "Identify the consonant blend in the word \"thrust\":",
          "options": [
            "thr",
            "ru",
            "ust",
            "hr"
          ],
          "answer": 0,
          "explanation": "The word \"thrust\" contains the consonant blend \"thr.\""
        },
        {
          "questionNo": 7,
          "question": "Which word has a three-letter consonant blend?",
          "options": [
            "supply",
            "splice",
            "spark",
            "slip"
          ],
          "answer": 1,
          "explanation": "The word \"splice\" contains the consonant blend \"spl.\""
        },
        {
          "questionNo": 8,
          "question": "Identify the consonant blend in the word \"crash\":",
          "options": [
            "cr",
            "h",
            "ra",
            "ash"
          ],
          "answer": 0,
          "explanation": "The word \"crash\" contains the consonant blend \"cr.\""
        },
        {
          "questionNo": 9,
          "question": "Which of the following is a three-letter consonant blend?",
          "options": [
            "tr",
            "dr",
            "spl",
            "br"
          ],
          "answer": 2,
          "explanation": "The consonant blend \"spl\" is a three-letter blend."
        },
        {
          "questionNo": 10,
          "question": "The word \"strand\" contains a three-letter consonant blend.",
          "options": [
            "True",
            "False"
          ],
          "answer": 0,
          "explanation": "The word \"strand\" contains the three-letter consonant blend \"str.\""
        },
        {
          "questionNo": 11,
          "question": "Which word has the consonant blend \"spr\"?",
          "options": [
            "sparrow",
            "spread",
            "sport",
            "spurt"
          ],
          "answer": 1,
          "explanation": "The word \"spread\" contains the consonant blend \"spr.\""
        },
        {
          "questionNo": 12,
          "question": "Identify the consonant blend in the word \"planet\":",
          "options": [
            "pl",
            "la",
            "an",
            "nt"
          ],
          "answer": 0,
          "explanation": "The word \"planet\" contains the consonant blend \"pl.\""
        },
        {
          "questionNo": 13,
          "question": "The word \"glide\" contains a consonant blend.",
          "options": [
            "True",
            "False"
          ],
          "answer": 0,
          "explanation": "The word \"glide\" contains the consonant blend \"gl.\""
        },
        {
          "questionNo": 14,
          "question": "Which of the following words contains a three-letter consonant blend?",
          "options": [
            "scam",
            "class",
            "brave",
            "strike"
          ],
          "answer": 3,
          "explanation": "The word \"strike\" contains the three-letter consonant blend \"str.\""
        },
        {
          "questionNo": 15,
          "question": "Which word contains the three-letter consonant blend?",
          "options": [
            "sparkle",
            "spade",
            "splice",
            "spell"
          ],
          "answer": 2,
          "explanation": "The word \"splice\" contains the three-letter consonant blend \"spl.\""
        },
        {
          "questionNo": 16,
          "question": "The word \"test\" has the final consonant blend of \"sk\".",
          "options": [
            "True",
            "False"
          ],
          "answer": 1,
          "explanation": "The word \"test\" has the final consonant blend of \"st\"."
        },
        {
          "questionNo": 17,
          "question": "Which of the following has the final consonant blend of \"nd\"?",
          "options": [
            "last",
            "mask",
            "cold",
            "tend"
          ],
          "answer": 3,
          "explanation": "The final consonant blend \"nd\" consists of the letters 'n' and 'd', which are present at the end of the word \"tend.\""
        },
        {
          "questionNo": 18,
          "question": "Which of the following words contains a three-letter consonant blend?",
          "options": [
            "sprint",
            "scope",
            "train",
            "break"
          ],
          "answer": 0,
          "explanation": "The word \"sprint\" contains the three-letter consonant blend \"spr.\""
        },
        {
          "questionNo": 19,
          "question": "The word \"crunch\" contains two consonant blends.",
          "options": [
            "True",
            "False"
          ],
          "answer": 0,
          "explanation": "The word \"crunch\" contains the consonant blends \"cr\" and \"nch.\""
        },
        {
          "questionNo": 20,
          "question": "The “l” final consonant blend would be “-ld” in “cold”.",
          "options": [
            "True",
            "False"
          ],
          "answer": 0,
          "explanation": "In the word “cold,” the final consonant blend is “-ld.” A consonant blend consists of two or more consonants together in which each consonant sound is heard."
        }
      ]
    }
  ]
}
